ELISABETH SEMEL PAPERS (APAP332) 1977-2012
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Elisabeth Semel Papers1977-2012
nam_apap332
Elisabeth Semel's papers primarily consist of articles published from the 1990s to early 2000s used by Semel in her research and work concerning the death penalty.
8.66
Semel, Elisabeth A.
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Elisabeth Semel 2012.
Biographical History
Elisabeth A. Semel began her law career when she graduated from the School of Law at the University of California, Davis in 1975. She practiced privately from 1980 to 1997, working solo until she created Semel and Feldman as a partner in 1983. In 1997 she began serving as the director of the American Bar Association Death Penalty Representation Project in Washington, D.C., where she remained until 2001.
When Semel left D.C., she returned to California to become an Acting Clinical Professor at Law at Berkeley Law. In 2005 she became the first director of the Berkeley Law Death Penalty Clinic, and a Clinical Professor at Law, positions that she holds today. At the Clinic, Semel supervises students who represent clients facing the death penalty during all stages of the proceedings. Her research focuses on the role of race in the administration of the death penalty, and includes representation in juries.
Over the course of her career, Semel has published many articles and opinion pieces on the subject of the death penalty and related criminal justice topics. She often comments in mainstream media on current death penalty topics and issues, particularly the rights of those facing a death sentence. She has received several awards including the Outstanding Legal Service Award from the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty in 2008, and most recently the Death Penalty Focus Abolition Award in 2011.
Scope and Content Information
Semel's papers, for the most part, contain articles about the death penalty published over the last few decades. The articles cover either specific state or federal cases, or issues related to the death penalty such as race, mental illness, or public opinion. The collection also includes court transcripts from select cases, and a couple of surveys performed regarding the death penalty.
The collection has been divided into two series; one for specific cases arranged by state and the other for topics related to the death penalty. Within Series 1, all federal cases have been placed under "Federal" first, then arranged alphabetically by the title of the file.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series: Cases and Issues and Topics.
Series 1 - Cases and Surveys, 1981-2012
Series 2 - Issues and Topics, 1977-2009
Subject and Genre Headings
Death Penalty; Semel, Elisabeth A.; Capital punishment; Discrimination in capital punishment; Articles; Criminal court records; Transcripts
Container List
- Cases and Surveys, 1981-2012; 1; 5.66
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains articles pertaining to specific cases, arranged by state and then by last name of the case subject. The list includes the District of Columbia and is missing four states: Alaska, North Dakota, West Virginia, and Wyoming. California is the most represented, carrying more extensive materials in the cases of Robert Alton Harris, Michael Morales, and Darrell "Young Elk" Rich. Similarly, Texas contains more material for Juan Garza and Thomas Miller-El. Federal cases are filed under "Federal" and then arranged alphabetically from there with the section consisting mainly of death penalty surveys, material on Timothy McVeigh, and a few other federal cases. Various surveys that have been conducted on the death penalty are included along with the articles.
  - ACLU - Alabama Death Penalty Study, October, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ACLU - The Hidden Death Tax, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ACLU - Death by Geography, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alabama - Anniston Star Series, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alabama - 2000-2001, 1999-2001; 2004; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alabama - 2002-2003, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alabama - 2004, 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alabama - 2005-2009, 2005-2008; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arizona, 1997; 2000-2004; 2007; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arkansas, 1997; 1999; 2001-2002; 2004; 2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bakersfield Californian - Special Report, December, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Birmingham News - Death Penalty Series, November, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - California - Allen, Clarence Ray, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - California - Babbitt, Manny, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - California - Beardslee, Donald, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - California - Death Penalty, Through 1999, 1997-2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - California - Death Penalty, 2000-2002; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - California - Death Penalty, 2003, 2000; 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - California - Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - California - Death Penalty, 2005-2007, 2005-2008 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - California - Death Penalty Statistics, 1993; 1995-1996; 2002; 2006-2008; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - California - Death Row, San Quentin, 2003; 2005-2008 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - California - Diaz, Robert, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - California - Filings, Kevin Cooper, 2001; 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - California - Gay, Kenneth, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - California - Governor's Race, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - California - Habeas Corpus Resource Center, 1994; 1996-1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - California - Harris, Robert Alton, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - California - Harris, Anti-Death Penalty Opinion, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - California - Harris, Defense Attorneys, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - California - Harris, European Reaction, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - California - Harris, Execution, 1992-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - California - Harris, Federal Courts, 1981; 1990; 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - California - Harris, Letters to the Editor, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - California - Harris, Personal Background, 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - California - Harris, Pro-Death Penalty Opinion, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - California - Harris, Protestors/Demonstration, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - California - Harris, Psychiatric Letter to Wilson, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - California - Harris, Fetal Alcohol Syndrome-Religious Reaction, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - California - Harris, Sevilla, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - California - Harris, State Court, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - California - Harris, Victims, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - California - Harris, Wilson, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - California - Kelly, Horace, 1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - California - Mason, David vs. Vaquez, 1993; 2001 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - California - Massie, Robert, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - California - Mental Retardation Bill, 2001-2002; Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - California - Morales, Michael-Clemency, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - California - Morales, Michael-Habeas, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - California - Morales, Lethal Injection News Articles, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - California - Morales, Lethal Injection Litigation, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - California - Siripongs, Jay, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - California - State Bar Capital Appeals Report, 1981; 1990-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - California - Stolen Justice Mercury, Criminal Justice Series, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - California - Supreme Court, 1992-1993; 1995; 2000-2002; 2004-2008; Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - California - Rich, Darrell Keith (1 of 2), 1988; 1997; 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - California - Rich, Darrell Keith (2 of 2), 1988; 1997; 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - California - Rich, Darrell "Young Elk", 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - California - Rich, Darrell-Media, 2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - California - Thompson, Thomas, 1996-1998; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - California - Williams, Keith, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - California - Williams, Stanley, 2000; 2003; 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Colorado, 1997; 2000-2003; 2007; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Connecticut, 1999; 2001-2002; 2004-2005; 2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - District of Columbia, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Delaware, 2000-2004; 2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Federal - Ashcroft Report, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Federal - Ashcroft Testimony, June, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Federal - Ashcroft June Hearing and Testimony, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Federal - Ashcroft Testimonies, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Federal - Ashcroft E-mails, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Federal - Death Penalty Survey (1 of 3), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Federal - Death Penalty Survey (2 of 3), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Federal - Death Penalty Survey (3 of 3), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Federal - Death Penalty Before 2001, 1997-2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Federal - Death Penalty (1 of 2), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Federal - Death Penalty (2 of 2), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Federal - Death Penalty, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Federal - Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Federal - Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Federal - Death Penalty, 2005-2007 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Federal - Kazcynski, Ted, 1998-1999; 2001; Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Anti, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Timothy-Clippings (1 of 2), 2001-2002; 2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Timothy-Clippings (2 of 2), 2001-2002; 2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Pleadings May-June, 2001; Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Pleadings (1 of 2), 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Pleadings (2 of 2), 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Pro, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Trial (1 of 4), 1997; 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Trial (2 of 4), 1997; 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Trial (3 of 4), 1997; 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Trial (4 of 4), 1997; 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Federal - Missaoui, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Federal - Nichols,Terry, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Federal - Quinones, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Florida - 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Florida - 1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Florida - 1999, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Florida - 2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Florida - 2001 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Florida - 2002, 2002-2004 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Florida - 2003, 2001; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Florida - 2004-2007 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Georgia - The Atlanta Journal Constitution Series, 2007-2008; Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Georgia - Through 2004, 1999-2003; Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Georgia - 2007-2008, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Georgia - Moore, Billy, 1984; Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Georgia - Williams, Alex, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Hawaii, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Idaho, 2000-2003; Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Illinois - 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Illinois - Cases, 1991; 1996; 1998-2004; 2007; Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Illinois - Chicago Tribune Death Penalty Series, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Illinois - Clemency, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Illinois - Counsel, 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Illinois - Cruz, 1998-2002 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Illinois - Legislation, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Illinois - Moratorium, 1999-2000; 2002; 2005 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Illinois - Opinions, 1999-2003 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Illinois - Porter, Anthony, 1999-2000; 2003 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Illinois - Ryan, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Illinois - Ryan, Commission Report Press File, 2002; 2004 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Indiana, 1996; 2000-2005; 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Indiana Series - Other Lottery 2001, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Iowa, 1998; 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Kansas, 2001; 2003; 2005; 2007 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Kentucky, 1997-1998; 2000-2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Louisiana, 1998-2005 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Maine, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Maryland - Pre 2003, 1991; 1997-1998; 2000-2004; Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Maryland - 2003-2006, 2002-2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Maryland - 2007, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Maryland - Colvin-El, 1999-2000; Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Massachusetts, 1997; 2001; 2003-2007 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Michigan, 1997-2000; 2002; 2004 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Minnesota, 2000-2001; 2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mississippi, 1997-2004; Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Missouri, 1997-2002; 2006; Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Missouri - Amrine, 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Missouri - Mease, Darrell, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Missouri - Richardson, Antonio, 2001; 2003; 2007 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Montana, 1999; Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Nebraska, 1999-2003; 2005; 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Nebraska - Study, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Nevada, 2000-2004; Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - New Hampshire, 1998; 2000; 2004; 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - New Jersey - Through 2004, 1997-2006 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - New Jersey - 2006-2007, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - New Mexico, 2001-2004; 2007 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - New York - Cases, 1996-2004; 2006 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - New York - General, 1996; 1998-2008 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - New York - Legislation, 1998-2005; 2007; Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - New York - Opinions, 1999-2007 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - North Carolina - 2004-2006 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - North Carolina - 2007, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - North Carolina - Cases, 1999-2001; 2003; 2005 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - North Carolina - Counsel, 2002-2003; 2006 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - North Carolina - General, 2000-2004; 2006 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - North Carolina - Judges, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - North Carolina - Legislation, 2000-2001; 2003-2004; 2006 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - North Carolina - Moratorium, 2000-2003; 2007 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - North Carolina - Opinions, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Ohio, 2000-2007; Undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Oklahoma, 1993; 2000-2004; 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Oklahoma - Gilchrist, Joyce, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Oklahoma - Sellars, Sean, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Oregon, 2000-2002; 2004 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Pennsylvania - 2000-2004, 1998-2004; Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania - 2006-2008, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Rhode Island, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - South Carolina - 2002, 1998-2002 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - South Carolina - 2003, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - South Carolina - 2004, 2006; Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - South Carolina - 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - South Dakota, 2000; 2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Tennessee, 1999-2004; 2006-2007; Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Tennessee - Death Penalty Series, July, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Texas - 2004, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Texas - 2005-2006, 2004-2006; Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Texas - 2007, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Texas - Banks, Delma, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Texas - Beazley, Napoleon, 2001-2002; Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Texas - Burdine, Calvin, 2000-2003 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Texas - Cases, 1997-2005; 2012 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Texas - Counsel, 1998-2004; 2006 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Texas - Dallas Morning News, Batson Series August, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Texas - DeLuna, Chicago Tribune Innocence, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Texas - Faulder, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Media List, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Reno/Department of Justice Articles, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Reno Press Statement, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, White House Articles, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles (1 of 2), 2000 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles (2 of 2), 2000 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Bush Articles, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Bush Transcripts, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Department of Justice Articles and Transcripts, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Texas - General, 1997-2004 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Texas - Graham, Gary, 1998; 2000; Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Texas - Houston Chronicle Series, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Texas - Legislation, 1999-2003 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Texas - McGinn, Ricky, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Texas - Mentally Retarded, 1999-2004 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Texas - Miller-El, Thomas News File, 2000-2004 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Texas - Miller-El, Thomas Media Round 2, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Texas - Miller-El, Media Post 2005 Reversal, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Texas - News Stories, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Texas - Opinions, 1998-2005 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Texas - Penry, 1999-2001; 2003; Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Texas - Robison, Larry, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Texas - Rojas, Leonard, 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Texas - Tucker, Karla Faye, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Texas - Yates, Andrea, 2001-2002; 2005 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Utah, 2002-2004 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Vermont, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Virginia - Breard, Angel Francisco, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Virginia - Cases, 1997-2006 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Virginia - Coleman, Roger Keith, 1992; 2000-2003 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Virginia - General, 1997; 1999-2005; 2007 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Virginia - Jackson, Chauncey, 1998; 2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Virginia - Kasi, 1997-1999; 2002 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Virginia - Legislation, 1998; 2000-2002; 2007 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Virginia - Opinions, 2000-2004; 2008 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Virginia - Retardation, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Virginia - Walton, Percy, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Virginia - Washington, Earl, 1994; 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Virginia - Williams, Terry, 1998-2000; Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Virginia - Wright, Dwayne, 1998; Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Washington, 2001-2003; 2007 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Washington - Seattle P-I Series, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Wisconsin, 2003; Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Issues and Topics, 1977-2009; 2; 3
  This series contains articles covering different issues dealing with the death penalty including costs, public opinion, and race. The largest sections are counsel, mental retardation, and opinions, with articles from the 1990s to the early 2000s. Notably, the opinion section contains articles on international opinion as well as domestic views on the death penalty.
  - Capitalism, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chicago Tribune Confession Series, December, 2001-2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Conditions, 2001; 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Costs (1 of 2), 1991-1995; 1998-2006; 2009; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Costs (2 of 2), 1991-1995; 1998-2006; 2009; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Counsel - Pre 2000, 1990; 1993; 1996-2000; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Counsel - 1990s-2000s, 1993; 1997-1998; 2002-2004; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Counsel (1 of 2), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Counsel (2 of 2), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Counsel - January-June (1 of 2), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Counsel - January-June (2 of 2), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Counsel - July-December, 2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Counsel, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Counsel - 2003, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Counsel - 2004, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Counsel - 2005-2007, 2006-2007; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Crime - Prevention, 1990-1998; 2000; 2002; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Crime - Public Perception, 1992-1998; 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Crime - Statistics, 1992-2000; 2002-2003; 2008 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Habeas - Loss of, 1991-1992; 1995-1997; 1999-2001; 2007; Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Innocence - Exoneration After Execution, 1999-2001; 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Innocence - Life After Death Row, 1998-2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Innocence - Non-DNA, 1998-2004 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Innocence - Overviews, 1993-1994; 1997-2001; 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Innocence - Protection Act, 1999-2002; 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Juveniles - Pre 2000 (1 of 2), 1994-1996; 1998; 2007; Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Juveniles - Pre 2000 (2 of 2), 1992; 1995-1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Juveniles, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Juveniles, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Juveniles, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Juveniles - 2002-2003, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Juveniles - 2004, Simmons (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Juveniles, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Kendall, George Speeches, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mentally Ill, 1998-2007 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mentally Retarded - Pre 2000, 1991; 1993; 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mentally Retarded - 2000, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Mentally Retarded - 2001, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mental Retardation - 2000, 2002, 2002-2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mental Retardation - 2004, 2004-2005; 2007 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Mental Retardation - Atkins Response, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mental Retardation - HRW Report 2001 (1 of 2), 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Mental Retardation - HRW Report 2001 (2 of 2), 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mental Retardation - Legislation, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Non-Death, Chicago Tribune, October, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Opinion - Anti-Death Penalty: Growing Public Opinion, 2002-2006 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Opinion - Anti-Death Penalty, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Opinion - Conservative Opposition, 2000-2001; 2003-2005; Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Opinion - Editorials, Anti-Pre 2000, 1977; 1982; 1990-2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Opinion - Editorials, Anti-Pre 2001, 1999-2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Opinion - Editorials, Anti-2000-2001 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Opinion - Editorials, Anti-2000-2001 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Opinion - Editorials, Anti-2004-2005, 2002-2005; 2007; Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Opinion - Editorials, Anti-2005-2007 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Opinion - International, 1999-2000, 1996-2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Opinion - International, 2001, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Opinion - International, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Opinion - International, 2004, 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Opinion - Pro, 1977; 1999-2002; 2004; 2006; Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Opinion - Public, Through 2000, 1992; 1995; 1997-2000; 2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Opinion - Public, 2001-2002, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Opinion - Public, 2003-2004, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Opinion - Public, 2005-2006, 2001; 2005-2007 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Politicians, 1993; 1995; 1999-2005; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Prison Conditions California (1 of 2), 1991; 1994-2001; 2004-2006; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Prison Conditions California (2 of 2), 1985; 1987; 1991-1995; 1997-1999; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Profiles, 1995; 1998-200; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Prosecution Misconduct, 1992-1994; 1997-2005; 2007; Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Prosecution Misconduct - Chicago Tribune, Pre 2000, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)